

# **Juan David Rueda**

**Mechatronics Engineer** 



# CONTACT

Santander, Colombia

in linkedin.com/in/juan-rueda-m

#### LANGUAGES

Spanish.

English. B2

French, A2

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming: Matlab, C#,
   Python, Full stack web, MongoDB,
   MySQL, Express, React, Astro,
   Wordpress, NodeJS, Azure Cloud,
   Node red.
- 3D Modeling: SolidWorks, Fusion 360, NX, Blender, Inventor.
- IT: Cisco Packet Tracer, VirtualBox, Wireshark, Linux, subnetting, fundamentals in TCP/IP, ethical hacking and virtual machines.
- **XR**: Unity 3D, webAR, Oculus.

## INTERESTS

- Instruments and sports.
- Full stack web development.
- Virtual and augmented reality web development.
- System design.
- · Cybersecurity.
- Cloud computing.
- Industry 4.0.
- Traveling

#### **PROFILE**

Mechatronic Engineer highly qualified in programming, specialized in the MERN stack. Thanks to my ability to communicate effectively and my enthusiasm for learning, I have successfully led multidisciplinary projects, enhancing seamless collaboration between technical and non-technical teams. I strongly believe that the combination of my background in mechatronics engineering, full stack web development, IoT, programming, automation and control, XR technologies, 3D modeling and IT can drive innovation and generate significant impact with my future team, enabling the development of unique and advanced solutions that will result in a smarter and more efficient future. I am excited to contribute to technology growth and be part of a visionary team that shares the same passion for excellence and continuous improvement.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Junior researcher

UNAB - ICP Ecopetrol, Remote Job | Oct 2022 - Jul 2023

- Development of a Cyberphysical system with the integration of a digital twin in technologies such as NodeJs, Matlab and ThreeJs.
- Development of a Network Control System (NCS).
- Development of a web application for remote control and monitoring of an oil drilling scale equipment.
- Scientific research of books, papers and conferences to make contributions in the area of interest.

#### Freelancer Developer

*Trenzar Memorias*, Remote Job | Apr 2023 - May 2023 *Club Anacondas*, Remote Job | Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

• Wordpress development for both projects.

#### **Software Developer**

Human Bionics, Bucaramanga | Jan 2022- Jun 2022

- Videogame development.
- Virtual and augmented reality development.
- Development of web pages and mobile applications.
- IoT development. Integrations with Amazon's assistant, Alexa.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Mechatronics Engineer**

UNAB, Bucaramanga | Jan 2017 – Nov 2022